Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm 5976 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Correspondence 1937-1940 (Reel 5)
  - 0913. September 21-December 1940. 133 pages., 8 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman contract; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; stake in World War II of organized labor and Negroes; increased benefits for unemployed railroad workers; illegal crediting of rest periods; brutality toward porter; National Railroad Adjustment Board decision on Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute; Pullman porters convention; relief assignments; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman negotiations; pay rates for porters on the Southern Pacific; resolutions offered by the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; labor planks of the Republican and Democratic party platforms; efforts by organized labor to defeat the Patman Bill.
- Correspondence 1941-1943 (Reel 6)
  - 0001. January-March 1941. 82 pages., 1 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: instances of discrimination against Negroes; Illinois State Commission on the Condition of the Urban Colored Population; porters' working conditions and hours; agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company; dues collection; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; seniority rosters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary organizations; contract with the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad; Illinois unemployment compensation law; agreement between the Southeastern Carriers Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; overtime.
  - 0083. April-July 1941. 95 pages., 2 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Overtime; National Action Conference for Civil Rights; dues collection; list of porters on the New York Central Railroad System; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; porter grievances; reports on porter operations; patterns of National Defense Mediation Board settlements.
  - 0178. August-December 1941. 107 pages., 3 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Reorganization of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; porter grievances; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Illinois Central contract; salaries and expenses; memorandum of agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Alton Railroad Company; Illinois civil rights legislation; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters division heads.
  - 0285. January-April 1942. 85 pages., 4 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company safety news; salaries and expenses; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Negro locomotive firemen; porter work schedule for the Alton Railroad Company; deadhead service.
  - 0370. May-June 1942. 106 pages., 5 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Salaries and expenses; delinquent members; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; March on Washington movement; plans for a Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters youth program; porter work schedule for the Alton Railroad Company; porter grievances.
  - 0476. August-December 1942. 150 pages., 6 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Victory Jubilee; memorandum of agreement between the Alton Railroad Company and the Dining Car Employees Union; Union for Democratic Action program; salaries and expenses; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention in Saint Louis; efforts to organize Negro locomotive firemen in the South; Midwest Workers Education Conference; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; National War Labor Board procedures for controlling the adjustment of wages of railroad workers; discriminatory employment practices in the railroad industry; recommendations for changes in the social Security Act; proposed national system of unemployment compensation.
  - 0626. January-August 1943. 148 pages., 7 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: International race problems; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Labor League for Human Rights; race riots in the United States; business meetings of the Chicago division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.
  - 0774. September-December 1943. 92 pages., 8 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Efforts to abolish poll tax; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; group insurance benefits for Pullman employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters scholarship fund; Fair Employment Practices Commission directives ordering abolition of racial discrimination on southern railroads; membership lists.
- Correspondence 1944-1945 (Reel 7)
  - 0001. 1944. 152 pages., 1 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: War Labor Board directives; Office of Price Administration food ceiling price list; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; increase in salaries for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; race discrimination; voter registration; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters resolutions; complaints against porters; President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice; porter grievances; Wallace Corporation versus National Labor Relations Board; Steele versus Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company et al; molestation case; Franklin Roosevelt's declaration on racial discrimination; employee withholding exemption certificates.
  - 0153. January-June 1945. 75 pages., 2 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: National Conference of Pullman Car Cleaners and Yard Forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; transfer of dues for Illinois Central porters; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; railroad annuity pension tax; demerit system of discipline on the Chicago and Northwestern Railroad.
  - 0228. July-December 1945. 86 pages., 3 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Support for United Negro College Fund; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; list of officers of the local divisions of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters twentieth anniversary retrospective; Department of Labor information bulletin; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters representation for Pullman yard and shop employees; anti-labor bills in the United States House of Representatives; wage demands of Illinois Central employees; instructions for members of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization committee.
  - 0314. Mimeograph copies - 1, 1945. 87 pages., 4 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: National Railroad Adjustment Board racial discrimination case involving train porters; porter grievances; Pullman disciplinary actions against porters; negotiations for paid vacations; Santa Fe Railroad porters and attendants join Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; operation of extra porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters claims on behalf of porters.
  - 0401. Mimeograph Copies - 2, 1945. 114 pages., 5 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; wages and working conditions of Union Pacific chair car men.
  - 0515. Mimeograph Copies - 3, 1945. 91 pages., 6 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Memorandum of agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Minneapolis, Saint Paul, and Sault Saint Marie Railroad Company regarding vacation allowances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; vacation pay for Aton Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters named authorized representative of porters of the Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances.
  - 0606. Mimeograph Copies - 4, 1945. 114 pages., 7 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters named authorized representative of porters of the Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad Company; Car Cleaners and Yard Forces Conference; revision of Pullman working conditions agreement; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman car cleaners and yard forces; porter grievances; porter wage agreement; report of proceedings of the National Conference of the Representatives of Santa Fe Train Porters.
  - 0720. Mimeograph Copies - 5, 1945. 113 pages., 8 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.
  - 0833. Mimeograph Copies - 6, 1945. 152 pages., 9 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
- Correspondence 1945 (Reel 8)
  - 0001. Mimeograph Copies - 7, 1945. 120 pages., 1 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Porter grievances; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.
  - 0121. Mimeograph Copies - 8, 1945. 147 pages., 2 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters recognized as representative for porters on the Santa Fe Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago and North Western Railway Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
  - 0268. Mimeograph Copies - 9, 1945. 132 pages., 3 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Vacation agreement with Alton Railroad Company; record of number of conductors, porters, attendants, and bus boys displaced from regular assignments; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman yard forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
  - 0400. Mimeograph Copies - 10, 1945. 135 pages., 4 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Alton Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
  - 0535. Mimeograph Copies - 11, 1945. 110 pages., 5 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances.
  - 0645. Mimeograph Copies - 12, 1945. 88 pages., 6 (Reel 8)
    Major Topic: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.
  - 0733. Mimeograph Copies - 13, 1945. 125 pages., 7 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; conference of Pullman car cleaners and yard forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Southern Pacific dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Santa Fe train porters and Pullman car cleaners and yard forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping car Porters- Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board. Vacation agreement with the Chicago and North Western Railroad Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
- Correspondence 1945-1946 (Reel 9)
  - 0001. Mimeograph Copies - 14, 1945. 122 pages., 1 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
  - 0123. Mimeograph Copies - 15, 1945. 98 pages., 2 (Reel 9)
  - 0221. Mimeograph copies - 16, 1945. 110 pages., 3 (Reel 9)
  - 0331. Mimeograph Copies - 17, 1945. 153 pages., 4 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; racial discrimination against porters by military personnel.
  - 0484. January-September 1946. 124 pages., 5 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad Company agreement on pay rates and working conditions and vacation agreement; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; work hours for Pullman storeroom nonclerical employees; travel expenses; American Federation of Labor convention; amendment of Railroad Retirement Act.
  - 0608. October 1946. 187 pages., 6 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor convention program; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; proceedings of the Firemen's Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in Birmingham, Alabama; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; work hours of Pullman storeroom nonclerical employees.
  - 0795. November-December 1946. 172 pages., 7 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Pullman Porters Benefit Association of America convention; furlough and recall of Pullman car service employees; list of dining car employees employed by the Chicago and North Western Railroad; National Mediation Board election for union representation of Pullman shop and yard employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; lists of Pullman shop and yard employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman car cleaners; national policy against discrimination in industry; problems of Negro veterans.
- Correspondence 1947-1957 (Reel 10)
  - 0001. January 1947-June 1948. 206 pages., 1947-1948; 1 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Hardships encountered by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters porters in Saint Louis District; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; National Mediation Board union representation election for dining car employees of the Chicago and North Western Railway Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize dining car employees of the Chicago and North Western Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters regional labor conference in Toronto, Canada; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; Illinois Fair Employment Practices Act; list of paid-up membership in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; list of furloughed and sick members in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division.
  - 0207. July 1948-December 1950., 1948-1950; 2 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; fight against Jim Crow in the armed forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters division officers; delinquent members; porter seniority list; monthly review of the Railroad Retirement Board; report of proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Southwestern Zone Conference Board; report of proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Southwestern Zone Conference; congressional hearings regarding the Fair Employment Practice commission; porter sleeping accommodations; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters negotiations with Chicago and North Western Railway company; porters' vacation schedule; vacation agreement with the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad.
  - 0405. 1951-1952. 165 pages., 3 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Porter vacation schedule; dues collection; porter seniority rosters; Joint Council Dining Car Employees-Chicago and North Western Railway company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; employee passes; negotiations with the Chicago and North Western Railroad; porter sleeping accommodations; pay increase for porters on the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad; Department of the Army instructions for operations of the railroad; porter grievances; payroll deduction plan for United States savings bonds; Pullman safety record; Veteran's Readjustment Assistance Act of 1952
  - 0570. 1953-1954. 165 pages., 4 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Veteran's Readjustment Assistance Act of 1952; porters' seniority rosters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters agreements with the Illinois Central Railroad Company and the Chicago and North Western Railway Company; porter sleeping accommodations; employee passes; election for officers of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; operations of extra employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules; porter pay rights.
  - 0755. January 1955-April 1957. 184 pages., 1955-1957; 5 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Porter seniority rosters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters regional zone conferences; operation of extra employees; financial standing of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members in Denver, Kansas City, Oklahoma City, Omaha and Saint Paul; porter vacation schedule; A. Philip Randolph elected American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations vice president; eligibility for railroad retirement annuities; porter grievances; Chicago and North Western Railway divisional territories; business meetings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; Bbrotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules; employee passes.
  - 0939. May-December 1957. 146 pages., 6 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Conference; passenger train accommodations; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; status of civil rights legislation; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters educational program; George Meany's address on civil rights in the United States; porter vacation schedule.
- Correspondence 1958-1961 (Reel 11)
  - 0001. 1958. 196 pages., 1 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations convention resolution on civil liberties and internal security; porter seniority rosters; Chicago and North Western Railway divisional territories; Pullman terminates group insurance plan; Labor Conference on Civil Rights; race hate propaganda by employers; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council statements on civil rights, housing, and blood banks; porter grievances; discontinuation of Pullman agencies; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman negotiations; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights program; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People charges of racial discrimination by unions; Fair Employment Practices Commission activities.
  - 0197. January-June 1959. 170 pages., 2 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples charges of racial discrimination by unions; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council statements on housing and civil rights; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights program; Labor Conference on Civil Rights; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.
  - 0367. July-December 1959. 165 pages., 3 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Problems of Negroes in organized labor; American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; porter grievances; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations policy resolutions on civil rights and civil liberties; members of the Railway Labor Executives' Association; amendments to Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution; list of New York Central porters; Emil Mazey's address on civil rights; segregation by unions.
  - 0532. January-May 1960. 67 pages., 4 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights public relations; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council statement on civil rights; establishment of a School of International Labor Studies at American University; report on civil rights for Negroes in trade unions; porter grievances.
  - 0599. June-December 1960. 81 pages., 5 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-New York Central union shop agreement; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organization Civil Rights Committee activities; porter seniority lists; segregation by unions; civil rights resolutions adopted by Indiana State American Federation of Labor-congress of Industrial Organizations Convention; Boris Shishkin's statement at the National Conference on Constitutional Rights and American Freedom; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Southern Advisory Committee on Civil Rights.
  - 0680. Hearings Register, 1955-1960. 56 pages., 6 (Reel 11)
    Major Topic: Information relating to porter complaints and union issues.
  - 0736. January-May 1961. 98 pages., 7 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Civil Rights Conference in Louisville, Kentucky; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; report on the federal executive and civil rights; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations public service programs; equal employment opportunity in federal government on federal contracts; porter rest periods; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago-Midwest and Saint Louis-Southwest zone conference.
  - 0834. June-December 1961. 95 pages., 8 (Reel 11)